ANKITA RAMESHCHANDRA PANDEY

AI/ML/NLP Data Scientist | Data Analytics | ML Specialist | ETL Developer

📞 +1 5712657779 @ ankitapandey@vt.edu 🔗 www.linkedin.com/in/ankita-pandey-721264188



EDUCATION

MS in Computer Science

Virginia Tech

08/2023 - 12/2024 US

GPA 3.43 / 4.0

Bachelor of Computer Science

VITI

08/2018 - 05/2021 India

GPA 3.6 / 4.0

EXPERIENCE

ML Intern

Virginia Tech, Sanghani Center for AI and Data Analytics

10/2023 - Present Virginia USA

- Optimized data retrieval using NLP techniques and the RAG model, collaborating with company professionals for a 25% efficiency boost
- Spearheaded the development of a project website for NLP-based RAG model, elevating project visibility by 30%

Graduate Data Analyst ETL Developer

Barclays 08/2021 - 07/2023 Pune India

- Innovatively developed an analytics tool using Tableau to validate the authenticity of internal business data against the source data, providing actionable insights to business stakeholders
- Spearheaded the development of a data pipeline for the NGCB project, significantly reducing the customer records comparison processing time by 85%, from 120s to 18s
- Demonstrated leadership by supervising two developers, creating a data-retrieving website, and establishing a CICD pipeline with Jenkins, JUnit testing, and Hadoop integration

Summer Data Intern

Barclays 06/2020 - 08/2020 Pune, India

- Conceptualized and executed a cost-effective and scalable private cloud storage solution using Raspberry Pi hardware, outperforming traditional alternatives.
- Led a project team in designing a system capable of storing and processing up to 1 terabyte of data.

Data Science Intern

VJTI 06/2019 - 08/2020 Mumbai India

- Pioneered the development of a sophisticated mobile forensic application that achieved a 98.5% data cleansing accuracy
- Conducted in-depth exploratory data analysis (EDA), revealing complex attack patterns and deploying advanced Artificial Neural Networks (ANN) to predict and prevent fraudulent activities with a remarkable 99.02% accuracy rate

CERTIFICATION

Big Data

Sai Aditya's Big Data Course: In progress

Google Data Analytics Specialization

Coursera, completed 2022

Advanced Python

Kamal Classes, completed 2021

Android

GPM, completed in 2018

LEADERSHIP



07/2019 - 05/2020

Orchestrated and supervised over 15 technical, cultural, and sports events, attracting 500+ student participants

Chief Sponsorship Executive

07/2018 - 05/2019

Managed funds for Enthusia, a national sports fest overseeing an impressive turnout of 2,000 participants

SUMMARY

Data scientist and analyst with 3 years of experience in ML and data analytics, expert in NLP, ETL development, and data visualization using Tableau. Achievements include optimizing data retrieval for a 25% efficiency boost and reducing customer records processing time by 85% at Barclays. Seeking a data scientist position at a company committed to leveraging data for strategic decision-making.

SKILLS

Ab initio	Machine Learning		Dec	Deep learning	
Analyzing (data	Pandas	CI/CD	Elastic	A
MySQL	Github	EXCEL	Al	RAG	
MongoDB	NLP	NLTK	Pych	arm ı	react.js
SQL P	ython	Scikit-Lea	ırn H	IDFS	Agile
LLM T	ableau de	esktop	Big data	Stati	stics
Tensorflow	Dat	a Mining an	d Analyti	cs Hi	ve
PowerBI	Matple	otlib Py	Torch	Spark	Jira
AWS p	predictive modeling Data mode			modeling	
Data Analy	tics	Data Mining	Nei	ural Netwo	ork
GCP D	ata struc	tures D	ata Scien	ice	

PROJECTS

Yogiction The Health Addiction

02/2021 - 07/2022 Mumbai, India Co-founder of a startup aimed to yoga

Founded a yoga startup, focusing on holistic promotion and engagement. Achieved 98% accuracy in posture recognition using Pose Estimation models.

Ghanta Gadi App

10/2019 - 08/2020 Mumbai, India Mobile App with ML capabilities

Developed a mobile app for NGO's waste management, improving sorting efficiency by 50% and reducing costs by 30% using machine learning-driven EDA and predictive models

Driverless Car

07/2019 - 05/2020 Mumbai, India

Team Leader and ML specialist, car system.

Engineered a smart vehicle with 95% accuracy in motion analysis, 97% accuracy in image recognition, and precise obstacle detection. Successfully conducted real-road tests for traffic signal navigation, pedestrian detection, and drowsy driver identification.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Winner: National Level project competition

Won first in 150+ project in competition with an innovative Driverless Car.



Captured Women's Basketball Trophy; a testament to teamwork